<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows Azure on Cloud Artisan</title><link>https://cloudartisan.com/tags/windows-azure/</link><description>Recent content in Windows Azure on Cloud Artisan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudartisan.com/tags/windows-azure/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IronRuby on Rails on Azure (Part 2 of 3) – Connecting your Rails app to SQLAzure</title><link>https://cloudartisan.com/posts/ironruby-on-rails-on-azure-part-2-of-3-e28093-connecting-your-rails-app-to-sqlazure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudartisan.com/posts/ironruby-on-rails-on-azure-part-2-of-3-e28093-connecting-your-rails-app-to-sqlazure/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the continuation of my bungling around with IronRuby, Rails and getting it running on SLQAzure. In part 1, we installed a basic rails application using IronRuby with SQL Server as it&amp;rsquo;s backend. We&amp;rsquo;ll now examine how we can connect this application to a SQLAzure backend as opposed to a SQL Server hosted on your development machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m assuming you have the vanilla rails application from Part 1 up and running and have verified that the rails application can communicate with your SQL server database by clicking on the “About your application’s environment” link as described in the previous article. I’m also assuming you’ve already signed up for a SQLAzure account and know how to connect to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IronRuby on Rails on Azure (Part 1 of 3) - Getting Started</title><link>https://cloudartisan.com/posts/ironruby-on-rails-on-azure-part-1-of-3-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudartisan.com/posts/ironruby-on-rails-on-azure-part-1-of-3-getting-started/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of a three part series on running a rails application on Windows Azure using SQLAzure as your database backend. The Rail Guides website, of course, has a wonderful getting started &lt;a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly do justice. This small series is just a very simple demonstration of one possible way of developing a rails application on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll simply be focusing on getting a basic rails application running on your laptop or desktop using IronRuby and SQL Server and links to download bundles that you can try out for yourself. If you already know how to do all that, skip to the end of this article to the download bundles and head over to Part 2: Connecting your rails application to SQLAzure&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>